Louise Elliott

Phone: 07749319196 | Email: louise.elliott.work@gmail.com | Bournemouth, UK

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/louise-elliott-work

GitHub: https://github.com/louise-elliott-work
Portfolio: https://louise-elliott-work.netlify.app

Summary

Driven and always keen to learn and adapt. Effective at problem-solving, identifying areas for improvements and supporting colleagues with up-skilling and implementing change. Known as a conscientious professional with a keen eye for detail and a passion for making a difference. Experience working in a variety of socially responsible roles. Qualified foster carer providing alternative care at weekends and during school holidays. Skillset of ever-expanding web development tools and technologies alongside varied child development expertise supported by primarily self-sourced training and development.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJS, ES6, Node.js, APIs, EmailJS, CLI.

Projects

React Portfolio | https://github.com/louise-elliott-work/react-portfolio | https://louise-elliott-work.netlify.app

- Summary: This app provides a polished portfolio. It utilises React routings for smooth navigation between pages that show a professional summary, key projects to date and contact details. Projects are displayed in a modified Bootstrap carousel taking data from a json file that can be simply added to. The contact form employs useState and emailJS for effective functionality.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: React, JavaScript, SDK, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML

PupVenture | https://ibalan92.github.io/dog-friendly-locations | https://github.com/ibalan92/dog-friendly-locations

- Summary: This app provides users with a list of dog-friendly destinations. The
 user inputs the date and a location and will see nearby destinations and the
 weather forecast for that date. Additionally, the user can save locations as
 favourites.
- Role: Developed the app as part of a four-person team, contributing the relevant share of lines of code and commits.
- Tools: APIs, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Education

Sep23 - present

Front End Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: edX

100% achieved to date. An intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJS, ES6 and Node.js. Emphasis on teamwork and collaboration throughout.

Sep16 - Jul17

Post Graduate Certificate in Education - Languages: University of Brighton

A practical course about how people develop, consolidate and deepen their knowledge and understanding of language in different contexts. QTS awarded. 60 Masters credits.

Sep07 - Jul11

Bachelor of Science (Hons) International Management and Spanish: University of Bath First Class achieved. A four-year degree focused on the international business environment and the global economy. Third year spent working in Chile in audit and SAP.

Experience

Teacher of Languages2017-2024Kingdown SchoolWarminster, UKSt Bartholomew's SchoolNewbury,UK

OIX

Bohunt School Wokingham, UK

Taught French, Spanish, English and Literacy to pupils aged 11-18.

Key accomplishments:

- Delivered tailored support to pupils with 100% A level results above target.
- Communicated effectively with parents/carers, colleagues and other professionals.
- Identified and completed key training and disseminated key findings to colleagues.

Internal Auditor 2015-2016

International HIV/AIDS Alliance

Brighton, UK

Carried out audits of partner organisations and head office procedures.

Key accomplishments:

- Carried out audits in Cambodia, Ecuador, Peru, Kenya, Ukraine and Namibia.
- Identified priority risk areas and recommended action points.
- Wrote clear and comprehensive reports summarising findings for key stakeholders.

Conservation Partnerships Administrator

2013-2015

Programme Finance Officer, Americas & Caribbean

2012-2013

Fauna & Flora International

Cambridge, UK

Provided financial, administrative and governance support to the organisation's five thematic teams and to the Americas & Caribbean team.

Key accomplishments:

- Streamlined communication, resource use and strategy plans across the 5 teams.
- Met 100% of internal and external financial deadlines.

•	Compiled expenditure reports for \$0.5m annual project budget.